Kyle Zapcic

Software Engineer

kzapcic@gmail.com • (714) 642-5586 • Charlotte, NC

Portfolio • Github • LinkedIn

SUMMARY

Software engineer and former real estate broker with a passion for programming. I possess the technical skills of an engineer coupled with a demonstrated knowledge of the real estate industries. Experienced in full brokerage, comparative market analysis, client service, contracts, and negotiations.

SKILLS - React, JavaScript, Node, is, TypeScript, Next, is, Express, Redux, MongoDB, Java, SpringBoot, Git/Github, Docker, AWS, SQL, PostgreSQL, CSS, HTML, VSCode.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Redfin Corporation, Irvine, CA and Charlotte, NC

September 2016 – Present

Senior Sales Broker

- Advocated for client success in real estate transactions, managing market analysis, client relationships, and multiple projects
- Achieved lifetime sales of more than \$100M+ across over 150 transactions,
- Provided feedback to Product Management on new Agent Tools features, influencing UX enhancements
- Participated in Software Development Mentorship program, discussing system design, CI/CD, microservices

Yardi Systems, Irvine, CA

August 2014 - April 2015

Technical Account Manager (RentCafé)

- Led RentCafe portal implementations, integrating with Yardi Voyager and several other complementary products, for mid-size and enterprise multifamily clients.
- Scoped projects, defined goals, and coordinated cross-functional teams to meet timelines and deliverables.
- Successfully implemented 20+ projects and identified/debugged client-specific issues to ensure client success.

Vidcaster, San Francisco, CA

September 2013 - April 2014

Sales Consultant

- Sold custom web video library display solutions
- Partnered with product, engineering, legal, and marketing teams to align roadmaps with customer feedback.
- Developed scope of work and professional services for implementations

APPLICATIONS

Christmas Wishlist - React, JavaScript, Java, Spring, Docker

Live Site | Github

Dynamic wishlist item tracker helping you plan the holidays better.

- Developed the full Java Spring Boot back-end API, building models, endpoints, and routes. Deployed with Docker.
- Implemented a React front end with integrated components, using best practices for state management.
- Orchestrated full user authentication with error handling, password hashing, and validation.

Rightsize Meals - Node.js, Handlebars.js, Bootstrap, Postgres, Sequelize

Live Site | Github

Full-stack application that allows users to discover calorie and food recommendations.

- Integrated the Handlebars templating engine for applications primary user interface.
- Created site design and user experience with Bootstrap.
- Incorporated an external Food API to fetch information on calorie info to track intake.

House Compass- React, Google Maps Javascript API

Live Site | Github

Real estate app helping users search and find the direction of any address

- Designed and developed a fully functional React app with dynamic Google Maps API integrations
- Implemented responsive, modern UI/UX using Tailwind CSS and optimized performance with Vite.
- Deployed the application on AWS, ensuring scalability and reliable accessibility.

EDUCATION

UNC-Charlotte, Charlotte, NC Graduate of the Full-Stack Software-Engineering curriculum. June 2024

University of Massachusetts-Commonwealth Honors College, Amherst, MA

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration (Cum Laude)

May 2010

Oxford University, Oxford, UK

July 2006

English Literature Certificate

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Coding Certificates: Codecademy HTML, CSS, and JavaScript courses.

Real Estate Licenses and Certifications: Broker: California-2016, North Carolina-2022, South Carolina-2023